Harleigh B. Trecker Papers 1986.0008
Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
- Series IV: Research Files, undated, 1921-1964
  - Board Member's Manual—Greater Waterbury (Box 15:, Folder 380)
  - Training Council Boards—Girl Scouts (Box 15:, Folder 381)
  - Mr. President—American Trade Association Executives (Box 15:, Folder 382)
  - What Decisions do Trustees actually Make? LeRocher and Howard (Box 15:, Folder 383)
  - Report from Your Executive—The Children's Village (Box 15:, Folder 384)
  - Role of the Board in Voluntary Agencies (Box 15:, Folder 385)
  - Who Are They...? (Box 15:, Folder 386)
  - American Cancer Society Members' Conference, 1959 (Box 15:, Folder 387)
  - Program Guideposts for Local Easter Seal Societies (Box 15:, Folder 388)
  - Mark of an Effective Board, Dr. Ray Johns (Box 15:, Folder 389)
  - Jewish Community Newsletter (Box 15:, Folder 390)
  - Mobilization for Youth (Box 15:, Folder 391)
  - Board of Directors—YWCA (Box 15:, Folder 392)
  - Citizen Boards in State Welfare Departments (Box 15:, Folder 393)
  - Criteria Form—YMCA (Box 15:, Folder 394)
  - Fresh Perspectives on Program Planning—YWCA (Box 15:, Folder 395)
  - Letter to John Pihley of Providence Youth Progress Board from HBT (Box 15:, Folder 396)
  - Executive Role with Boards—UConn School of Social Work (Box 15:, Folder 397)
  - Principles (Box 15:, Folder 398)
  - Appendix A (Box 15:, Folder 399)
  - Citizen Advisory Board in Public Welfare—National Conference on Social Welfare (Box 15:, Folder 400)
  - What are the Responsibilities of Center Boards of Directors?—Jewish Centers Association (Box 15:, Folder 401)
  - Handbook for Board and Delegate Members—American Cancer Society (Box 15:, Folder 402)
  - Handbook for Volunteers—Family Services Association (Box 15:, Folder 403)
  - Blueprint for Board Members, Della Schmidt (Box 15:, Folder 404)
  - So You're on a Committee!—American Trade Association Executives (Box 15:, Folder 405)
  - Directly for Directors—American Trade Association Executives (Box 15:, Folder 406)
  - Board Orientation Study Kit—National Society for Crippled Children and Adults, Inc. (Box 15:, Folder 407)
  - Study of the Decision—Making Progress in Girl Scouts Council Boards of Directors, Berkeley School of Social Work (Box 15:, Folder 408)
  - Trustees of the Community's Health and Welfare Program—New Orleans, Louisiana (Box 15:, Folder 409)
  - Executive and the Agency Board, Charles Levy (Box 15:, Folder 410)
  - Board Membership Characteristics—Memphis, Tennessee (Box 15:, Folder 411)
  - Volunteer Management—Allegheny County, Pennsylvania (Box 15:, Folder 412)
  - Boards and Board Members of Health and Welfare Agencies—Community Chests and Councils of America, Inc. (Box 15:, Folder 413)
  - Director's Duties and Responsibilities, Carlton Spencer (Box 15:, Folder 414)
  - Bulletin of the Russell Sage Foundation Library (Box 15:, Folder 415)
  - Ideology, Status and Power in Board-Executive Relationships, Ralph Kramer (Box 15:, Folder 416)
  - Handbook for County Welfare Board Members—Minnesota (Box 15:, Folder 417)
  - What is a Conference? H. LeRoy Marlow (Box 15:, Folder 418)
  - Board of Directors of a Neighborhood Center—The National Federation of Settlements and Neighborhood Centers (Box 15:, Folder 419)
  - Board Members Kit—Connecticut Tuberculosis and Health Association (Box 15:, Folder 420)
  - Head Start Newsletter (Box 15:, Folder 421)
  - PTA Magazine, 1968 (Box 15:, Folder 422)
  - YMCA Boards and Committee of Management Family Service Highlights (Box 15:, Folder 423)
  - Boards and Board Members—Community Chests and Councils of America, Inc. (Box 15:, Folder 424)
  - Newsletter—Girl Scouts, 1961 (Box 15:, Folder 425)
  - The Council Manual—Girl Scouts [No. 19-172, 20-171] (Box 15:, Folder 426)
  - Community Welfare Council—Milwaukee, Wisconsin (Box 15:, Folder 427)
  - Board Members' Manual—Visiting Nurse Association of Springfield, Massachusetts (Box 15:, Folder 428)
  - Summary Talks on Developing an Effective Agency—Rhode Island Council of Community Services (Box 15:, Folder 429)
  - Board Members' Manual—National Publicity Council for Health and Welfare Services (Box 15:, Folder 430)
  - Board Members' Workshop—Flint, Michigan (Box 15:, Folder 431)
  - Volunteers Board of Members in Philanthropy—National Information Bureau (Box 15:, Folder 432)
  - Leadership—National Association of Manufacturers (Box 15:, Folder 433)
  - Functions of a Board of Directors—Girl Scout Leadership (Box 15:, Folder 434)
  - Board Member Page—Child Welfare (Box 15:, Folder 435)
  - Cues for Chairman—Girl Scout Leader, 1956 (Box 15:, Folder 436)
  - Building Board Leadership—National Jewish Welfare Board (Box 15:, Folder 437)
  - Board Members Institute—Greater Hartford Community Council, 1960 (Box 15:, Folder 438)
  - Board Members Institute—Greater New Britain Community Council (Box 15:, Folder 439)
  - Institute for Board Members—Akron, Ohio (Box 15:, Folder 440)
  - Board Member of a Family Agency—Family Welfare Association of America (Box 15:, Folder 441)
  - Guide to Styles, Groups, Methods, YMCA Magazine (Box 15:, Folder 442)
  - Board, Executive and Staff—Hermay Stein (Box 15:, Folder 443)
  - Board Members Manual—National Service Organization, Detroit (Box 15:, Folder 444)
  - Board Members Manual—Public Health Nursing Organization of Eastchester, New York (Box 15:, Folder 445)
  - School Boards (Box 15:, Folder 446-447)
  - Social Groups (Box 16:, Folder 448-455)
  - Boards (Box 16:, Folder 456-457)
  - Unidentified (Box 16:, Folder 458-459)
  - Newburgh Affair (Box 16:, Folder 460)
  - Poverty (Box 16:, Folder 461)
  - Schools (Box 16:, Folder 462)
  - Student Protest Material (Box 16:, Folder 463-465)
- Series V: Framed Objects, undated, 1955
  - Photograph of Harleigh B. Trecker (Box 17)
  - National Association of Social Workers certificate
  - Photograph of Old School of Social Work
  - Photograph of New School of Social Work
  - Dr. Harleigh Trecker, Teacher and Friend photograph
  - Multi-National Youth Leadership photograph, 1955
  - American Association of Group Workers Board, 1955
- Series VI: 1997 Addition, undated
  - Admin. Skill in Leadership for Social Change with clippings, notes, correspondence, and reports/books with a Ch. 12 notation on most of the material, undated (Box 18)
  - 7 Admin Skill in Resource Development and Accountability with clippings, notes, correspondence, and reports/books with a Ch. 7 notation on them, undated (Box 18)
  - Selected readings, with handwritten notes and clippings of articles from journals, undated (Box 18)
  - Clips Fall 1980 with newsprint clippings, journal articles and reports, circa 1980 (Box 18)
  - 5 Administrative Skill in Goal Setting Priority Setting with clippings and handwritten notes, undated (Box 18)
  - Report from the National Center for Citizen Involvement, A Look at the Eighties: Crucial Environmental Factors Affecting Volunteerism, undated (Box 18)
  - 6 Admin. Skill in Motivating Persons to High Productivity with clippings, notes, correspondence, and reports, undated (Box 18)
  - Clips 11/15/80 Ch. 12 (newspaper clippings), circa 1980 (Box 18)
  - First Three Chapters Rough Draft Admin. Skill book, undated (Box 18)
  - MS of book with annotations and newspaper clippings, undated (Box 18)
  - Hartford Graduate Center with notes and clippings, undated (Box 18)
  - "Citizen Participation in the American Federal System" from the Advisory Commission on Intergovernmental Relations, with annotation Ch. 3, circa 1976 (Box 18)
  - Guide for Agency Self-Appraisal by Harleigh B. Trecker, 1953 (Box 18)
  - Writing General with correspondence, notes, and clippings, undated (Box 18)
  - Articles written by Harleigh Trecker, undated (Box 19)
  - Clippings and reports, undated (Box 19)
  - Material used in Chapter 3, undated (Box 19)
  - Chapter 2 materials pages 63-83, undated (Box 19)
  - 2 Changing Human Services in the Changing Community with handwritten notes, undated (Box 19)
  - Materials for Ch. 7, typed manuscript of one of the chapters and clippings, undated (Box 19)
  - Personnel Administration Manual for Community and Students YWCAs, undated (Box 19)
  - Mr. Tesar correspondence, news print material and a notebook, undated (Box 19)
  - 8 Admin. Skill in Coalition Leadership, undated (Box 19)
  - Notes and newsprint clippings, undated (Box 19)
  - 3 Admin Skill in Community Relationships, undated (Box 20)
  - Higgins, Don--correspondence and information, undated (Box 20)
  - Mason, James--correspondence and information, undated (Box 20)
  - Typescript of articles by Trecker with annotations, undated (Box 20)
  - Dubrof,Rose (Director, Brookdale Center on Aging, Hunter College)--correspondence and information, undated (Box 20)
  - The Travelers Older Americans Program, undated (Box 20)
  - Articles and reports, undated (Box 20)
  - Newsprint clippings and typescript, undated (Box 20)
  - 11- Admin. Skill in Service Delivery and Evaluation, undated (Box 20)
  - 9 Admin. Skill in Long Range Planning, undated (Box 20)
  - 10 Admin. Skill in Information Gathering, Utilization, Ret., undated (Box 20)
  - 4 Admin. Skill in Leadership and Management, undated (Box 20)
  - Outlines and related correspondence, undated (Box 20)
  - Nova Perspectivas De Administraçã by Harleigh Trecker, 1967 (Box 21)
  - Typescript of The Administrative Skills in the Human Services for the 80's by Trecker and correspondence, undated (Box 21)
  - Walsh Supervision of Volunteers, undated (Box 21)
  - Articles by Trecker, undated (Box 21)
  - Gardner, Sid (Hartford Chamber of Commerce)--correspondence and information, undated (Box 21)
  - Newspaper clippings with notes, undated (Box 21)
  - 1 Administrative Skills An Overview, undated (Box 21)
  - Federal Probation, 1979 June (Box 21)
  - UConn SSW-At Issue (HBT article), 1980 Fall (Box 21)
  - FPWA Guide to Good Meetings, undated (Box 21)
  - Maurice O. Hunt, Federation of Welfare Agencies, undated (Box 21)
  - Columns for Joe Zita (Better Boards), undated (Box 21)
  - Carbon, Dion--correspondence and TS of article, undated (Box 21)
  - S.C.C. with TS, clippings and notes, undated (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, 1977 (Box 21)
  - Galley proof of Social Work Administration, 1977 (Box 22)
  - Galley proof of Citizens Board at Work, undated (Box 22)
  - Galley proof of Social Group Work, undated (Box 22)
  - Galley proof of Social Work Administration, 1971 (Box 22)
  - Galley proof of Social Work Administration, 1977 (Box 22)
  - Galley proof of Working with Groups, committees, and Communities, undated (Box 22)
  - Galley proof entitled "Working", undated (Box 22)
  - "How to Work with Groups, Committees and Communities" copy #2, undated (Box 22)
  - Social Group Work (Japanese), H.B. Trecker, 1972 (Box 22)
- Series VII: 2014 Addition
  - plaque, 1966-1967 (Box 21)
    Scope and Content Note
    A plaque from the National Association of Social Workers Northern Connecticut Chapter in honor of Harleigh Trecker as Social Worker of the Year.
  - plaque, 1941-1957 (Box 21)
    A plaque for Harleigh Trecker in Appreciation for notable Contributions to the Progress of Social Group Work and Outstanding Service to the Welfare Council of Mwtropolitan Los Angeles 1941-1957.
  - certificates, 1941-1968 (Box 21)
    Deframed certificates awarded to Harleigh Trecker, and a photographs of the University of Connecticut School of Social Work.
  - Accession 2014.0135, 1977-1978 (Box 21)
    Folder containing manuscript of Reflections on the Art of Teaching by Harleigh B. Trecker.